So guys, now we're going to do some straight crunches.
So go ahead align yourself on the floor, bring your feet about shoulder width apart, have your feet flat on the ground, interlace your fingers behind your head and try to relax your head into your hands.
When you exhale I want you to crunch up, I want you to focus on your heart and move in your ribcage towards your pelvis.
Don't worry about coming up too high, just work to get your shoulder blades up off the ground and feel that you're engaging your abdominals each and every time.
It's really important for you just to feel that you're engaging your abdominals.
We'll get plenty of work on the abdominals as we progress.
Now after you do your first set let's see about if we can make them a little harder.
Let's raise your legs up to a 90 degree angle on your hip and your knee and keep your feet off the ground and let's do another set of 10 or 15 here.
Once after you finish that let's make them a little harder again.
Let's put your feet on the ground, squeeze your knees together, your feet together.
I want you to exhale and as you crunch up try to lift your knees up too so that your elbows and knees will touch midway.
Again, focus on pulling the belly button in towards your spine, bring the elbows up to touch the knees and then all the way back down.
It's really important to come back down to the floor each and every time.
Go for it!